Guide to the Varian, Inc. Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Records, Accession ARCH-1999-077
  - Unboxed Oversize Items, Subseries 4
    - Framed Photos: Aerial view of Varian lot; Varian Costume Party 48-58; 5th Anniversary
    - Poster - 50 Years, Growth Through Innovation
    - Matted Photo - Ed Ginzton and Meryl Stearns, by Ansel Adams
    - Photos on Boards: Young patient treated on Clinac; VAR begins trading on NYSE; Early optical spectroscopy product; 8 unlabelled (includes first Varian building in San Carlos, Sigurd and Russ Varian, W. Hansen)
    - Plaque on wood: congratulations to Ginzton on 30 years at Varian, with signatures
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2005-128
  - Audiotapes
    - 1. Varian 10th Anniversary Tape 1 Russ Varian etc., Nov. 2, 1958; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 2. Varian 10th Anniversary Tape 3 Ginzton, Nov. 2, 1958; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 3. Dr. Fred Terman gives history of electronics in Bay Area to Palo Alto Chamber luncheon, 5/27/1963; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 4. Jack McCullough, 1975; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 5. S.F.D. Lab Follies Songs dedicated to E. Ginzton, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 6. Withor (?), Sege, Sterns, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 7. Chodorow, Donavan, Maltzer, Ralph Kane, Ted Maring, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 8. A Tribute: Ed Ginzton, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 9. T. Sege, R. Horn, R. Powell, R. Kane, M. Chodorow, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 10. Eimac 50th Anniversary Interviews:Jacqueline Spearman, Edward Ginzton, Mona Jenkins, Michelle Lazer, Ray Riordan, Irv Coutts, Ann Kochly, Aug. 1984 (Box 1)
    - 11. Dorothy Varian, Julie Cameron (Box 1)
    - 12. Ginzton retirement - misc. interviews (Box 1)
    - 13. Ed Ginzton's story of Varian Founding, for 1974 employee service awards banquet (Box 1)
    - 14. Ginzton (Box 1)
  - The Bloomberg Forum, Tracy O'Rourke Interview [NTSC DUB], 1 videotape(s) (VHS); videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Ephemera: Who Are We [employee guide to Varian, Inc.], 2003 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2006-062
  - Varian Network, July 1986-June 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Varian Network, July 1988-June 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Varian Network, July 1990-June 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Varian Network, July 1992-June 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Varian Network, July 1994-September 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Currents, December 1995-April 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Currents, May 1997-Nov./Dec. 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Vintage Varian, inserts on Varian history for Currents (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Varian Magazine, June 1962, 1977-78 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Varian Magazine, 1979-80 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Varian Magazine, 1980-82 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Varian Magazine, 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Varian Magazine, 1990-91 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Varian Magazine, 1992-95 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Varian's 50th Anniversary: memos, correspondence, notes, 1997-98 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 50th Anniversary Events Committee (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Press releases, news clippings, 1998-99 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Varian Associates history: miscellaneous materials (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Varian Timeline (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Old Timers/Varian Firsts (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - VAR Celebrates 50th Anniversary - press release and one historic photo, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Varian Associates: historical materials (mostly articles) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - VAR 50th Anniversary history (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Remarks, Shareholders Meetings 1988-90 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Presentations to Security Analysts, 1982-90 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Quarterly Reports (brochures) 1987-90 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1976 Annual Report photographs (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1979 Annual Report photographs (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1980 Annual Report photographs (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, assorted (includes Russell and Sigurd posing with Klystron and first VA building) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photographs from last VA board meeting, February 1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Code of Business Ethics [Varian 1989; 2 copies] (Box 4)
  - Varian Marketing Communications, a Guidebook (Dec. 1993) (Box 4)
  - Varian Fifty Years of Innovative Excellence (1998; 2 copies) (Box 4)
  - Annual Report 1998 (Box 4)
  - Varian Associates: an Early History (Box 4)
  - Upside: 100 People Who Changed Our World (October 2001) (Box 4)
  - Notebook: Varian corporate identity manual (1977) (Box 4)
  - VA 50th Anniversary Video #7 Chromatography lab, April 8, 1998, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 5)
  - VA 50th Anniversary Video #8 Chromatography lab, April 1998, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 5)
  - VA 50th Anniversary Video #9 Chromatography lab, April 1998, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 5)
  - VA 50th Anniversary Video #10 Vista footage, April 9, 1998, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 5)
  - Varian Instrumentation Visuals for the Web, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 5)
  - Varian Quality Workshop, Feb. 1992; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - 900 MHz Magnet Installation - PNNL, March 13, 2002, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Labor Management Committee. "Blueprint for the Future", 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Varian Shareholders, 1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - 2 zip disks of Varian Currents, 1998 and undated, 2 computer media (Box 5)
  - 2 zip disks and 1 floppy of 50th Anniversary files, 2 computer media (Box 5)
  - 1 Varian eraser "Innovative people make technology work" (Box 5)
  - Varian identity standards manual, undated (Box 6)
  - First Varian Associates building (Box 6)
  - Files from the new company: Varian Inc.
    - PowerPoint presentation for stockholders' meeting February 8, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sampling of Varian Inc. newsletters, 1999-2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Stock and securities related reports, etc. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Press releases re Rogerson becoming CEO, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - First stockholders' meeting of Varian Inc., Feb. 10, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Varian, Inc. Development of a Comprehensive Identity Strategy (photocopy of overhead projection sheets) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Varian What's In a Brand Spring 2001 (photocopy of overhead projection sheets) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Early Varian, Inc. brochures (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Fact Sheet (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Backgrounder booklets: Corporate, July 2000 and March 2001; Vacuum Technologies, Oct. 2000 and March 2001 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Backgrounder booklets: Life Sciences, Sept. 2001; NMR, Aug. 2000 and Oct. 2000 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Drug Discovery (Varian's role in the drug discovery process) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Annual Report 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Clippings, general, Jan.-Mar., 2003 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, general, April-June, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, general, July-Sept., 2003 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, general, Oct.-Dec., 2003 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, general, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, scientific instruments, Oct.-Dec., 2003 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, scientific instruments, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Banners, early branding/identity program for Varian, Inc., ca. 2002 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Posters on operational excellence, 2000-2001, and branding/identity program for Varian, Inc., 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 2)